<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MovieBuddy</string>
    <string name="maps_api_key">AIzaSyAnIrJX8WMNRzHTwEVAcFIdl8pW2Wn_dRc</string>
    <string name="moviedb_api_key">e3933d5b5c409463ee2c85a307c0df96</string>
    <string name="youtube_api_key">AIzaSyAVN3pg7U4fEbSYPm_TKqHOypNUhTgK7bo</string>
    <string name="movie_name">Movie Title</string>
    <string name="movie_details">Movie Details</string>
    <string name="synopsis">Synopsis</string>
    <string name="rating">Rating</string>
    <string name="release_date">Release Date</string>
    <string name="sort_order">Sort Order</string>
    <string name="sort_key">Sort Key</string>
    <string name="sort_popular">Most Popular</string>
    <string name="sort_rating">Highest Rated</string>
    <string name="badboystitle">Bad Boys For Life’s Home Release Will Have An Alternate Ending And Tons Of Bonus Content</string>
    <string name="badboysnews">The COVID-19 pandemic has disrupted the film industry, particularly when it comes to movies that were supposed to be hitting theaters soon. Fortunately for Bad Boys for Life, it managed to enjoy a solid theatrical run ahead of this coronavirus craziness, and with that time on the big screen done, the movie is heading to home media soon, with an alternate ending being among the provided special features. Starting March 31, you’ll be able to buy Bad Boys for Life on Digital, and if you’d rather watch Will Smith and Martin Lawrence’s on Blu-ray, DVD or 4K Ultra HD, those physical copies will arrive on April 21. The Digital, Blu-ray and 4K Ultra HD versions of Bad Boys for Life come packed with over 50 minutes of special features, while the DVD version will have a handful of extras to enjoy. Given the need to keep spoilers quiet, no details about Bad Boys for Life’s alternate ending were provided. Considering how explosive the movie’s theatrical ending was, it’ll be interesting to see how things differ in this version. Did any characters who died in the finalized ending make it out alive instead, or vice versa? Or did the action beats just unfold differently in the journey to ultimately reach the same conclusion? We shall see. Other special features Bad Boys for Life will be providing in theDigital, Blu-ray and 4K Ultra HD include extended and alternate scenes and an easter egg tour guided by directors Adil El Arbi and Bilall Fallah, as well as the following featurettes: Ride or Die: Making Bad Boys for Life, Partners in Crime: Behind-the-Scenes, and It’s About Time, the latter of which delves into 25 years of Bad Boys history producer Jerry Bruckeheimer and the cast and crew. Coming out 17 years after Bad Boys II, Bad Boys for Life saw the return of Will Smith’s Mike Lowery and Martin Lawrence’s Marcus Burnett, with the duo investigating a string of murders tied to Mike’s past. Bad Boys for Life also brought back Theresa Randle’s Theresa Burnett and Joe Pantoliano’s Captain Conrad Howard, while the new cast members included Vanessa Hudgens, Alexander Ludwig, Charles Melton, Paola Núñez and Jacob Scipio, among many others. While Michael Bay, the director of the first two Bad Boys movies, was interesting in directing a third Bad Boys movie early into its development process, by 2018, Adil El Arbi and Bilall Fallah were brought aboard to helm the threequel (though Bay did still contribute in a fun way). Chris Bremner, Peter Craig and Joe Carnahan wrote the Bad Boys for Life screenplay. Critically speaking, Bad Boys for Life earned a lot of positive reviews and ranks at 77% among critics on Rotten Tomatoes, making it the highest-ranked Bad Boys movie on that website. Commercially, the threequel pulled in nearly $420 million worldwide off a $90 million budget, and as of this writing, it’s still the highest-grossing movie of 2020.</string>
    <string name="blackwidowtitle">In Inevitable News: Marvel Finally Delays Black Widow</string>
    <string name="blackwidownews">The past weeks news cycle has been dizzying, as the global COVID-19 pandemic changes daily life around the world. The ongoing situation has also sent shock waves through the entertainment world, as sets are shut down and movies are delayed. As large groups began dwindling around the world, movies like No Time to Die and F9: The Fast Saga were postponed seven months and a full year respectively. And as the situation continues unfolding, Marvel Studios has followed suit and pulled the release of Cate Shortlands Black Widow. This news comes to us from Variety, and is sure to be a bummer for the rabid Marvel fanbase. Black Widow was set to kick off Phase Four of the Marvel Cinematic Universe, while also providing closure with Scarlett Johanssons title character. Originally set to arrive on May 1st, Marvel and Disney have officially pulled the highly anticipated blockbuster. Whats more, theres no telling when it might actually hit theaters. The marketing campaign for Black Widow has been going full title for a few months now. The movies trailers were methodically released, and ads about Natasha Romanoffs long awaited solo flick are all over the internet and TV. And between the title characters fate in Avengers: Endgame and the killer cast Cate Shortland assembled, Black Widow really had momentum behind it before being pulled. While Scarlett Johansson was originally unsure about wanting to do Black Widow, the movies story ultimately inspired her to suit up one more time as the OG Avenger. Rather than being an origin story or traditional prequel, the delayed movie will be set in between the events of Captain America: Civil War and Avengers: Infinity War. Natasha should once again be a fugitive, and will be reunited with her original family, played by the likes of David Harbour, Florence Pugh, and Rachel Weisz. The trailers also reveled that Black Widow should contain flashbacks, and expand the title characters dark and sordid history. Natashas dark past has been alluded to a number of times throughout the MCU, but details have been limited. And now that the movie has been delayed, fans will have to wait even longer to get those answers theyve been hoping for. With so many movies being pushed back by various studios, 2021 is shaping up to be a wild one at the theaters. There were a number of huge blockbusters set to arrive next year before COVID-19 threw a wrench into plans for the entire industry. So will more be added for competition, or will we end up waiting years for certain releases? As far as Marvel goes, I am eager to see how the shared universe ultimately lands on a plan of action. Black Widow was supposed to start Phase Four, but could it end up being the second or third movie instead? Or will the studio simply shift all of its movies over one date to allow the original plan of release? The possibilities are endless, and only time will tell how the film industry recovers and moves on following the last week.</string>
    <string name="ghostbusterstitle">Ghostbusters: Afterlifes Finn Wolfhard Promises Faithful Continuation From The Original</string>
    <string name="ghostbustersnews">The original Ghostbusters had their adventures in the 80s but, now, a new team of heroes will rise to deal with paranormal activity in Ghostbusters: Afterlife. The highly anticipated sequel is set to expand on the universe established by the original two films, which has some veteran fans worried about just how closely Afterlife matches it predecessors. Well, never fear, because Afterlife star Finn Wolfhard thinks those fans will be pleasantly surprised. Wolfhard tells NME that fans shouldn’t worry because Ghostbusters: Afterlife will faithfully build on the classic films. In addition, he also believes the movie will appeal to younger fans by employing some key themes: "Older Ghostbusters fans will find it’s a really, really faithful approach to the series. While young people, if not everyone, will find that, first and foremost, Ghostbusters is about family and the relationships that these people have made. It’s also really funny, so I’m really excited for people to see it." From the moment fans got their first glimpse at the Ghostbusters: Afterlife trailer, it was more than evident that it’s leaning into nostalgic aspects of the franchise. That humor and sense of family that Finn Wolfhard mentions are also present. These are elements that are far from unfamiliar to the young actor, as the TV show he stars in – Stranger Things – employs these very themes. In terms of Afterlife, the idea of family is especially important since the film focuses on an actual family. Ghostbusters: Afterlife centers on a single mother who, with her two kids, moves to a farm in Oklahoma she inherited from the father she never knew. As time goes on, her children discover a connection between their family and the original Ghostbusters, which also illuminates the identity of their late grandfather. Many have already speculated that the grandfather in question will be Ghostbuster Egon Spengler, who was portrayed by the late Harold Ramis. Although details are scarce on how he’ll play into the film, Egon’s fate will indeed be addressed. Ramis’ absence will make the viewing experience somewhat bittersweet, but at least fans can still look forward to seeing the returning Bill Murray, Dan Aykroyd, Ernie Hudson, Sigourney Weaver and Annie Potts.</string>
    <string name="pottertitle">J.K. Rowling Doing The Dang Thing And Making Harry Potter Available During COVID-19 Crisis</string>
    <string name="potternews">To say the world has been shaken up over the last several weeks would be an understatement. The COVID-19 pandemic has brought so many industries to a grinding halt, and desperate times call for desperate measures… or at least being more flexible. Case in point, author J.K. Rowling is granting an open license for her Harry Potter books to teachers across the world as the coronavirus rages on. With schools being closed as a safety precaution, this open license will allow teachers to post videos of themselves reading the seven Harry Potter books aloud for their students. However, before any teachers reading get too excited and start posting a read-through of The Sorcerer’s Stone to YouTube, this relaxation of the standard copyright permissions only permits such videos to be posted onto “schools’ secure networks or closed educational platforms” from now until the end of the school year, or to the end of July for those in the summer hemisphere. In addition to providing a full set of guidelines for teachers to follow, the official announcement from J.K. Rowling’s website also mentioned that the open Harry Potter license is the first of “several initiatives being planned to help bring Harry Potter to children at home,” which will be announced soon. In the meantime, if you’re a teacher wanting to regain your students over the internet with tales of The Boy Who Lived, you can now for the next several months do so without suffering legal consequences. The Harry Potter book series began publication in 1997 with Harry Potter and the Sorcerer’s Stone, or as it’s known outside the U.S., The Philosopher’s Stone. The main saga concluded when The Deathly Hallows was published in 2007, and the Harry Potter film series ran from 2001-2011, with The Deathly Hallows being split into two movies. In the years since, J.K. Rowling also helped craft the story for the stage play Harry Potter and the Cursed Child, and various Harry Potter-related e-books have been released, though not all of them were written by Rowling. However, contrary to the rumor mill, another actual Harry Potter novel is not on the way, as Rowling considers that the hero’s story being closed after the events of The Cursed Child. Nowadays when it comes to the Wizarding World, J.K. Rowling has been focused on the Fantastic Beasts film series, which kicked off in 2016. She penned the screenplays for the first two movies, and she co-wrote the forthcoming Fantastic Beasts 3 with Steve Kloves, who wrote all of the Harry Potter movies except for The Order of the Phoenix. Fantastic Beasts 3 is currently scheduled to come out on November 12, 2021, and was supposed to begin filming last week, but because of the spreading coronavirus, it is among the many projects that’s had to halt production indefinitely. Depending on how long it takes to get cameras rolling again, it’s possible Fantastic Beasts 3 could be pushed back to 2022, but at least readers both young and old can keep themselves entertained with the Harry Potter books as the wait continues.</string>
    <string name="quietplacetitle">John Krasinski Explains Why A Quiet Place Part II Is Actually Scarier This Time Around</string>
    <string name="quietplacenews">The past few years have been a great time for horror fans, as the genre has experienced a bit of a renaissance. Countless critically acclaimed movies have hit theaters, resulting in box office success. 2018 brought us John Krasinskis directorial debut A Quiet Place, which was a huge hit and inspired a sequel. And according to director/writer of A Quiet Place Part II, its going to be even more terrifying than the original. A Quiet Place Part II was recently delayed due to concerns over the COVID-19 pandemic, but moviegoers are eager to see the highly anticipated horror flick arrive in theaters. Horror fans are particularly curious about just how scary it is, now that we understand the rules of the sound-focused aliens. But according to John Krasinski, the sequel will be even more terrifying than the first Quiet Place movie. As he recently explained, "I think you’re gonna be really scared. I mean the truth is, I think again organically you’re more scared because you care about these characters. In the first movie you were getting to know them. Now you know them, you don’t want anything to happen to them. The sound’s much more intense because you know the rules of sound. And so my point was to make the audience part of the movie." Hes got a point. At this point we know and love the Abbott family, who we watched throughout the course of the first Quiet Place movies runtime. As such, any danger they are in will no doubt inspire fear from the audience. Plus, they're out in the apocalypse with a baby. John Krasinski's comments to Extra Butter are sure to excite horror fans who are hoping to get a few good scares in when A Quiet Place Part II finally arrives in theaters. The director built a particularly sensory experience with the first movie. Because the characters are trying to make so little noise, the theater too falls completely silent. And when sound is introduced, it's anxiety inducing and terrifying as you wait for the aliens to burst in and kill the Abbotts. As the director pointed out, the audience will go into A Quiet Place Part II understanding the rules of the franchise. They won't have to slowly learn the stakes, but will be immediately cued into John Krasinski's apocalyptic vision. And since we care about the Abbott family (what's left of them), there will also be an emotional element to the moviegoing experience. A Quiet Place Part II will force Evelyn (Emily Blunt) and her children to leave the safety of their farm house, following the events of the first film. Lee sacrificed himself in the movie's third act, so she'll have to keep the rest of her family alive on her own. On the way they'll meet threats both alien and human, and seemingly anything could happen.</string>
    <string name="sonictitle">Ben Schwartz Has An On Brand Response To Sonic The Hedgehog Hitting Digital Early</string>
    <string name="sonicnews">The entertainment industry is scrambling to figure out how to handle the coronavirus outbreak situation. With movie theaters closed and new movie releases delayed, the entire focus of the movie business has shifted to digital releases. Now many movies are hitting digital much earlier than previously anticipated and now another film is going to hit video-on-demand in record time, though considering how fast he usually goes, maybe we should have seen this coming. The Sonic the Hedgehog movie is the latest to make the extra fast jump to digital platforms, as it will arrive on March 31. The voice of Sonic himself, Ben Schwartz, took to spreading the news with a very Sonic comment. "GOTTA GO DIGITAL FAST! Looks like #SonicMovie is coming to your homes digitally on March 31st!" Sonic the Hedgehog was just released in theaters in mid-February, and was doing well so it almost certainly would be in theaters right now, if there were any theaters to be in, of course. The major theater chains held out as long as possible, drastically reducing capacity to try and handle the coroavirus without actually closing, but eventually there was simply no choice. With Sonic the Hedgehog revealing a May date for its physical Blu-ray release, you have something of an idea when the movie was supposed to hit digital. Digital releases usually come no more than a couple weeks before the physical release, so the Sonic movie was likely expecting to hit digital in early May. Under the circumstances, ramping up production of the Blu-ray early isnt feasible. And also, buying the thing wouldnt be that easy anyway. Its not all that surprising that Sonic the Hedgehog is making itself available digitally right now, considering a host of movies that were even newer in theaters have also done the same thing. The Invisible Man, Bloodshot and other films that were basically brand new in theaters are available for online rental. Sonic, however, will be available for normal digital purchase. Trolls World Tour is already set to have a simultaneous opening digitally and in theaters, though that assumes theaters will be open when that movie arrives in early April, which is far from a sure thing right now. Sonic the Hedgehog will be a good addition to many digital lineups. It's a solid family film and with so many kids stuck at home with school's closed, it's just the sort of thing that might help in keeping them entertained under the circumstances. Of course, at some point we're going to run out of new movies digitally in the same way that we're out of movies in the theater. Of course, if this early digital release thing is successful, we could see movies doing this on a regular basis going forward. It will be very interesting to see how many of these emergency measures fade away once things return to normal and how many stay around for a long time.</string>
    <string name="spidermantitle">New Spider-Man 3 Rumor Includes One Of Netflix’s Marvel Heroes</string>
    <string name="spidermannews">The Marvel Cinematic Universe has become a well-oiled machine over the past decade of filmmaking, consistently entertaining and surprising the hardcore fandom. We are currently occupying the interim period between phases, and Black Widows delay makes this wait even long and more excruciating. One of the hotly anticipated projects coming down the pipeline is the third Spider-Man movie, and a new rumor indicates that it might bring a beloved Netflix Marvel hero onto the big screen for the first time. Prior to the inception of Disney+, Netflix produced five different shows set within the MCU (plus The Defenders miniseries). But the streaming service axed its entire slate of shows, with fans hoping the same cast of actors might finally crossover to the film world. The latest rumor about Spider-Man 3 says just this, indicating that Daredevil star Charlie Cox might appear alongside his fellow New York superhero. This rumor comes to us from Kevin Smith, who recently opened up about the possibility, saying: "I heard another piece of good fucking news. Did You hear that Spider-Man, the new Spider-Man movie, gonna have a lawyer in it? […] Charlie Cox, they’re bringing in as Matt Murdock. That’s been the rumor online and they say that’s like the one that like Marvel’s like god damn it how did that get out?" Do you hear that sound? It's Marvel fans everywhere cheering and collectively crossing their fingers. While this is far from a confirmation, the idea of seeing Daredevil on the big screen alongside Tom Holland's Spider-Man is enough to get fans very excited. We'll just have to see if that comes to fruition or not. Kevin Smith's comments come from his recent Fatman Beyond podcast. He admits that it's just a rumor at this point, but it's definitely a concept the filmmaker and comic book aficionado excited. After all, we've been waiting to see Charlie Cox's Daredevil on the big screen since he hit theaters in 2015. Since Spider-Man is a New York based superhero, it would be logical and easy for him to come into contact with Daredevil in Hell's Kitchen. And now that Peter Parker's identity was revealed thanks to J. Jonah Jameson, Matthew Murdock would have an easy time tracking down the wall crawler. Let's just hope he uses his classic costume again. All three seasons of Daredevil are currently streaming on Netflix, and Phase Four of the MCU will open up with The Eternals on November 6th. In the meantime, check out our 2020 release list to plan your next trip to the movies.</string>
    <string name="starwarstitle">Star Wars Explained Exactly How Palpatine Survived His Return Of The Jedi Fall</string>
    <string name="starwarsnews">The Skywalker Saga came to an end with J.J. Abrams Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker, and the conversation around the blockbuster hasnt slowed down since. In the months following Episode IXs run in theaters, plenty of exciting tidbits have arrived from interviews, comic books, and the movies novelization. The Rise of Skywalkers book greatly expanded upon the story, and answered the myriad questions that werent quite answered throughout its 142-minute runtime. Palpatines resurrection was a bit of a head scratcher, and now we know exactly how he managed to survive that fall in Return of the Jedi. Palpatine was seemingly killed in the third act of Star Wars: Return of the Jedi, with Darth Vader being redeemed shortly before his death. It was previously revealed that the Emperor we saw in The Rise of Skywalker was a clone, but now we know exactly how his consciousness managed to survive his apparent death aboard the second Death Star. As Episode IXs novel explained: "Plagueis had not acted fast enough in his own moment of death. But Sidious, sensing the flickering light in his apprentice, had been ready for years. So the falling, dying Emperor called on all the dark power of the Force to thrust his consciousness far, far away, to a secret place he had been preparing. His body was dead, an empty vessel, long before it found the bottom of the shaft, and his mind jolted to a new awareness in a new body - a painful one, a temporary one." It looks like Sheev Palpatine has been planning for his unexpected death throughout his life. In addition to crafting clones of himself, he was also prepared in a mysterious Sith ritual which allowed him to catapult his consciousness away from his physical form and into another. The Light Side doesn't practice this type of sorcery, but The Emperor was strong in the ways of the Dark Side. Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker didn't show or explain but, it turns out that Palpatine projected his mind outside of his body during that long fall, dying before his body ever hit the ground. Always a planner, The Emperor had already constructed the clone of himself that would ultimately pop up in Episode IX.</string>
    <string name="topguntitle">Tom Cruise Had One Big Request For Top Gun: Maverick</string>
    <string name="topgunnews">It’s been over 30 years since Top Gun first hit theaters, but franchise star Tom Cruise still has the need for speed. As most know, Cruise takes stunt work and spectacle very seriously, and he’s taken measures to ensure that the sequel, Top Gun: Maverick, is a thrilling follow-up. Although the actor went all in on helping to plan the effects, he did so on one key condition: "We just started talking. And I realized that there were things that we could accomplish cinematically. And I started getting excited about this big challenge of, ‘How do we do it?’ So I said to Jerry, ‘I’ll do it if…’ meaning, I’m not going to do the CGI stuff." Tom Cruise emphasized this desire for practical effects during a recent interview with Empire Magazine. According to the actor, he also used those early conversations with Paramount to stress just how big of an undertaking Top Gun: Maverick would be: "I said to the studio, ‘You don’t know how hard this movie’s going to be. No-one’s ever done this before.’ There’s never been an aerial sequence shot this way. I don’t know if there ever will be again, to be honest." Also, as previously alluded to, Cruise himself fully commits to any project he’s involved with. He learned to pilot a helicopter so that he could perform aerial stunts for Mission: Impossible – Fallout. And as we speak, he’s likely still working on death-defying stunts for the franchise’s latest installment, which was recently shooting in England. This can-do attitude has naturally seeped into his work on Top Gun: Maverick, as he and his castmates are said to have gone through grueling training to prepare for fligh. Aside from learning to fly jets, Cruise also does some motorcycle work in the film. The reward for injecting practical effects into a film can be great since they ultimately give off a realistic vibe that further immerses audiences into the cinematic experience. The only problem is that doing so can be both tedious and time-consuming. Yet many filmmakers still opt to take on the challenge in the hope that it will improve their art. Tom Cruise’s actions at the negotiating table and on set would indicate that Top Gun: Maverick has truly been a labor of love, one that he and his team have put a tremendous amount of thought into. There’s no telling how the final product will pan out, but things seem to be flying in the right direction. Top Gun: Maverick is set to soar into theaters on June 24.</string>
    <string name="venomtitle">No Big Deal, Just Tom Hardy And Woody Harrelson On The Venom 2 Set Before San Francisco Shutdown</string>
    <string name="venomnews">As of right now, it’s unclear if Venom 2 is going to make its release date. The film is currently scheduled to hit theaters on October 2, but the production has been shut down in recent weeks due to the COVID-19 pandemic, and it’s unknown if the project will be able to make up for lost time. It’s possible that we could wind up needing to wait until 2021 to see the blockbuster in its finished form – but at least for now we have some really great on-set photos of Tom Hardy and co-star Woody Harrelson to enjoy. We still haven’t seen any official images released from Venom 2 just yet, but at least we have some of the on-set work done by photographer Greg Williams, who was hired by the production to take behind-the-scenes snaps. While the movie was still filming, the production located in San Francisco, Williams was able to capture some really cool shots, including the one we see above. In Venom 2, directed by Andy Serkis, audiences will see the return of Tom Hardy as journalist Eddie Brock – who we watched go through quite a significant change back in 2018 when he became bonded with the titular alien symbiote. While Eddie was reluctant to work with the eponymous extraterrestrial goo at first, they became a pair by the end of the first Venom and decided that their relationship could be mutually beneficial. The upcoming sequel will feature a villain that fans have been clamoring to see on the big screen for years and years now, as Woody Harrelson will be playing Cletus Cassidy a.k.a. Carnage in the film. We were first introduced to the live-action incarnation of the character in the post-credits scene of Venom, where he found himself as one of Eddie Brock’s interview subjects while sitting in a prison cell, but it seems that Carnage won’t be spending all of Venom 2 in prison. Created by David Michelinie and Mark Bagley, Carnage was first introduced to the pages of Marvel Comics in February 1992 – a little less than four years after Venom became a fully-formed character. He is technically an offspring of his predecessor, and is best known in the comics for bonding with Cletus Cassidy, who is a sociopath and a homicidal sadist. Together they stir up all kinds of bloody mayhem, and Venom and Eddie Brock prove to be among the few that can stop them. While Tom Hardy and Woody Harrelson are all smiles here, one can assume that they won’t be smiling all that much when we see them on screen together in Venom 2, as they should make for very dangerous enemies. Not knowing anything about the plot of the film just yet, we don’t know much about their relationship in the story other than the fact that they will be foes, but we are certainly excited to learn more. In addition to Tom Hardy and Woody Harrelson, Venom 2 will also feature the return of Michelle Williams as Anne Weying and Reid Scott as Dr. Dan Lewis. And while we dont know what exact role she will be playing just yet, Naomie Harris will also have a role to play in the film, along with The Irishman’s Stephen Graham. As of right now, the movie is apparently still on track to be released in early October, but we’ll keep an eye on the situation as it continues to develop.</string>
</resources>
